Today there is a comparison video between
Nivaavoopa Health Rearsure and ICICI
Lombard Health Advantage. So we will compare both the plans and
see what are their features
and in the end we will talk about premia and you
can decide
which plan suits you as per your needs and for your retirement.
Before starting the video I would like to introduce myself.
My name is Goodlink. I
am a Certified Financial Planner. I have been associated
with the insurance industry for the last 17 years
and every week I bring you videos so that
your personal
financial life becomes easy and happy because the
tagline of our company is also
creating a wealth of happiness. Let's move on to the
video
vs ICICI Lombard Health. First we will
talk about claim settlement ratio and
incur claim ratio. Nivaavoopa's
claim settlement ratio is 96% and
denial ratio is 56%. ICICI
Lombard's claim settlement ratio is 93%.
And their claim ratio is 78%
which is around 8700 from hospital and
5100 of ICICI Lombard. Pan India
settlement is in-house for both the companies. There is
no external TPA. We will talk about the time shot.
Minimum time
is available in Surenia Booker Reacure. Five Luck maximum 5
crore minimum. Sameyi shot
is available in ICC Lombard Health and Vantage. Five Luck
maximum 3 crore minimum further. There is
91 days in both the policies and maximum is 65
years. Maximum dependent further means those who are
left in the policy can
continue for 30 years in this policy.
Whereas in Advantage, they can continue for 25 years. We will
talk about Policy 10, you
can take a policy of maximum 3 years. Option of 1 year, 2 years and 3 years
is available. You can do things as per your convenience
if you want to take 2 years.  If you pay a premium of three years
upfront, then some
companies also give you long term tenure discount.
In both the policy types, you
can take individual and family. If we
talk about room rent, there is
no room rent restriction in both the companies. You
can take any room. You can
take any room in the higher category. There is
no room rent restriction. If we
talk about dental care, there is
no need for 24-hour hospitalization. There are some
treatments which, due to the advancement of science, are
covered for 24 hours. If you go home within 24 hours, then that is the
case which does not require a minimum 24-
hour hospitalization.
So dental care treatments are also
covered in both the policies. There is a
refill benefit.
If your base water gets exhausted,
then the company gives you the option of refill. For
example, this is a glass. If the water in this glass gets
finished, then there are
different classes of refilling it.
So, for example, Neema, you  In the above mentioned area there
is an option of unlimited refills, which means I
can refill this glasses unlimited number of times, it means I can
refill it, it will get finished only once,
I can fill it once, I can do it without any worry,
any person can do it
and can do it with any lens, it is
free and post hospitalization, the
expenses before the hospitalization and if we talk about the expenses, then the expenses of
60 days before and 18 days after will be
covered in both the policies,
which you can cover,
both the policies are covered in this, domicile is not there, if
you want to get treatment at home, if there is
any such condition due to which you are
not able to go to the hospital, then that treatment
is covered for you or if there is no place available in the hospital
and you have to get treatment at home, then it is also
covered, so both the
policies cover home care treatment
by choice, if you do not want to go to the hospital, then
nivaafa is the best option for you,
ICICI Lombard Health  Advantage has
5% maximum 25000 no claim
bonus. No claim bonus is that if you do
not make a claim then the insurance
company incentivizes you and
gives you a bonus, so Nima is saying that in Sir,
50% off time shot will be given if you do
not make this claim, maximum it can go up to 100%
and if you make any claim then the
bonus will be reduced in the same proportion,
meaning for example if you have taken a policy of 10 lakhs and
you do not make any claim then
next year your policy will become 15 for 10, next year
it will become 20, now if
you make some claim from here then
proposedly then 15 for 20 and 10 for 15 will
continue in this manner, maximum it can increase only by 100%.
ICICI Lombard has a guaranteed
cumulative bonus, meaning once this
bonus is given, it is given for life time
- if you do not do so then 20% every year and
maximum mid can go up to that.  100% Emergency
Road Ambulance Road Ambulance is covered at a cost of
Rs. 2000 per hospital.
In ICICI Lombard Health and Advantage, now 1%
off time shot and maximum Rs. 10,000 will be given
but hospitalization,
pregnancy, air ambulance is also covered in this
domestic air ambulance. It is covered in both the
policies. So, see what are
its benefits. In this policy, up-to-
date insurance is available and
in case of reimbursement, if you go cashless, then you will get
summation. If you get reimbursement, you will get Rs. 2.5 lakh per
hospital. In ICICI Lombard
Health Advantage, it is covered up. Let's
talk about summation modern treatments.
Modern treatments and
robotic surgery are covered in this scheme.
Some surgeries are covered in this scheme. There is a limit of Rs. 1 lakh.
Modern treatments are covered in ICICI Lombard Health and Advantage.
Now you understand, now we will talk about
complimentary wellness test.
Insurance company gives you complimentary
wellness test so that you take
care of your health, now this is shown above
and gives you complimentary wellness test in
which ₹500 is ₹1000 time shot, that means if
you have taken a policy of ₹10 lakh then
you get complimentary wellness test of ₹5000
and if we have taken a policy of ₹20 lakh then ₹
10000, so maximum ₹10000 you are cashless and
can invest both, the
tests listed on this are listed for this, the
maximum you can claim for that is ₹10000
and here in ICICI Lombard only
cashless test is available, not in Revolut, it is
available in both, I would like to tell you that this
wellness test is available in many companies that on
renewal when you renew the policy then
this is complimentary well, in this loyalty
addition is given and oil bonus is given
but in both the policies
you lose 15-20 days after taking the policy  If you get the rest of the tests done,
you can claim in both the policies.
This is a complimentary benefit.
Organ donor coverage is covered in both the policies. Organ
harvesting is covered in both the policies. Ayush
hospitals,
Unani principles, homeopathy hospitals are covered in
both the policies.
Long term
hospitalization is a benefit in which if you are hospitalized for more than 10 days, then in
ICICI
Lombard Health Advantage, you will be given a loan of ₹20,000.
This is not available in ICICI Lombard Health Advantage. Tele
consultation is
consulting a doctor over the telephone.
This is an inbuilt feature in ICICI Lombard.
You can get tele consultations.
You can
take Best Consult plan in ICICI Lombard Health Rider or Smart Health Rider in Qute Care,
which comes at a very nominal cost, through
which you can cover tele consultations.
Next is Worldwide Cover. So
Worldwide Cover is
not available in
ICICI Lombard
Health Advantage, your policy will work only in India. In ICICI Lombard, if you have an investment of more than Rs 25 lakh.  If you
take the above policy, you
get worldwide cover. You
can get treatment anywhere globally. Your global
treatment is managed on a cashless
basis by Falcon International. They manage
your treatment and it is done on a cashless basis with a
10% copayment. Next is consumables
cover. If all of you want that
consumables should also be covered in your policy, that is, non-paper
items, should be covered, then you
can take a rider in the policy,
which has three benefits. First,
your non-payable items are covered.
Second, if your claim is
below Rs 50,000 in any year, then your notional
bonus is not affected. Third, your
time cover keeps
increasing according to your health. If you take a rider in your ICICI
Lombard Health Advantage, which is called
Claim Protector, then
consumables are covered. If you
want to cover other things, as I
told you, for inflation,
you will have to take a separate rider called Claim Protector.
OPD cover: OPD is
not covered in both the policies.  Yes, but you
can add additional riders. There is an option in both. In
short, you
can add Smart Health Rider, which we have just
discussed and in it there are two riders, Best Consult and
Best Care. You
can add them as per your need. If you
want to see its detailed video, then the
detailed video of the rider is also available. ICICI
Lombard has BF Rider which you
can add. Its detailed video is also available on our channel. Those
who want OPD
in their policy can check it out. So let
us talk about which additional riders
are available. Now we have discussed
some riders and combined them once.
Which additional optional riders
can you add, that is, those which are
not inbuilt in the policy, you can avail them by paying an extra premium.
Which we have just discussed is the Consumables
Cover Rider and you can avail riders from two other features.
You
can avail hospital cash benefit in which you will be
given hospital cash daily, maximum Rs.
4000 per
hospital.  You can get cash benefit.
Third is personal accidental cover. Now if you want to
add a rider for personal accidental cover which includes death and disability cover, then you
can absolutely do that. Fourth thing is that there
is no rider but you get a discount on medical practice.
If you are a medical
practitioner or a practicing doctor, then the
company gives you a 5% discount. Now let's
talk
about the riders of ICICI Lombard Health Advantage. One is
maternity right. Those who
want to take a maternity plan can look at
ICICI Lombard Health and Advantage. There is
maternity coverage in it. There is
1 baby coverage. Vaccinations are covered
for the first year. Along with the claim protectors which we just
talked about, I mean short
protector, this is also covered. There is another rider
which is called critical illness, which means that a
lump sum will be given in it if there is a
critical illness. Now let's talk about the
cover, but there is no payment in this cover.
Such people have the
option in our Health Advantage to make a payment of 10% or 20%.
Due to which your
premium will be reduced. Now coming to the
exclusions, what is the
waiting period of your policy or what things? There is an
initial waiting period of
30 days in both the policies. There is a specific exclusion of 30 days. The
specified illnesses,
slow growing illnesses, are
not covered. In Niva Bhupur, it is covered for 24 months and
2 years and
in ICICI Lombard Health Advantage also, it is
not covered for 2 years. Dear existing
conditions, there is a waiting period of 3 years, which means if there is
any illness before taking the policy, then there is a
waiting period of 3 years, 36 months and
24 months in ICICI Lombard Health Advantage, the waiting period is of 2 years.
Now let's talk about the premium, so
how much will your policy cost you? First
I would like to tell you that Neema Pur is divided into two zones,
Zone 1 and Zone 2. Your
premium depends on where you live.
You will have to pay it according to the zone. There are
three zones in ICICI Lombard Advantage,
Zone 2 and Zone 3 and the premium will be charged according to your zone. In
short, there is
no co-op payment if you
go from zone 2 to zone 3 for treatment, there is
no co-prime. And
in ICICI Lombard Advantage, if you
go from zone 3 to zone 2 for treatment, that is, from zone 3 to zone 2
or from zone 2 to zone 3, you can pay the
premium. Now, for example, I have taken a
family of
four, two adults
plus your husband, wife and two
children and I have taken the premium for zone 1. I have taken
45, 43, 15 and 12 and we
will see what is the premium for these. The premium for family
floater policy in 10 zones
is Rs. 24788, this is
including 18% GST for 1 year.
In ICICI Lombard Health and Advantage, it is Rs. 21703, this is also including
18% GST on both.  The premium will be changed in the company every 5 years,
so this was a comparison
from my side,
now you can see which
plan is suitable for you, you
can choose the policy according to the riders you want, if you have
any questions regarding both the plans,
you can send us
your WhatsApp number, email ID is mentioned,
you can also tell us in the comment section, if you have
any questions, you have some feedback, you
can also tell us that and if you want to tell us on what the
next video should be made, please tell me,
I will try to make it and
before leaving, a reminder, if you have
not yet subscribed to our channel, do subscribe so that you get the
right information and at the right
time and so if you find the information useful,
you can share it
with your friends and family so that they too can
get a Vijay division.  See you
next week, let's sit and
talk about organ donor
hospital.